Great. So, I'd like to now briefly introduce
myself and the other members of the teaching
staff. So, brief introduction, so my name
is Balaji Srinivasan. You can call me BSS
or Balaji S. I am a Stanford lifer. I did
all my education there. I also taught computer
science and statistics there before founding
a startup. That startup is called Counsyl.
It's been very successful. You can read these
links. Basically we scaled Counsyl from a
Stanford dorm room to a huge sixty thousand
square foot clinical genome center with two
hundred employees, around three percent of
U.S. births, and along the way we raised more
than sixty five million dollars in funding,
and here's a few article clips on Counsyl
in the New York Times, you know, Tech Crunch,
the Wall Street Journal and Scientific American.
And that's kind of the summary for me. You
can kind of read over those articles and get
a sense of my background. The next instructor,
Vijay Pande, will be teaching some of the
lectures toward the end of the quarter, or
the course rather. Vijay has his own Wikipedia
article. He's the director of the Folding@Home
project and an expert in distributed computing.
Here's a couple of clips on that. You can
take a look at this at Wikipedia, and also
at the folding.stanford.edu site. Finally,
this is the T.A., Alex Chia. Alex is Stanford
as well, MS in computer science, Carnegie
Mellon undergrad. He's won many programming
competitions and Alex will also be very active
on the forums.