Let's talk about collaboration and teams for
a little bit.
On the final project, can people work in teams?
I would prefer that you don't work in teams,
because it's kind of difficult and Coursera
isn't really set up for it. (Obviously in
real life, you're going to start a company
with a team, not as an individual, usually.)
But if you do want to work in teams, we can
try this as an experiment. The idea would
be that you would submit the graded portion
of each final project as individuals -- and
you can click this to see what I mean by the
"Graded portion," or the technical aspects
-- all of these you would submit your own
site, as an individual for technical grading,
while you'd leave the qualitative stuff all
rudimentary, in your own thing.
This way, if three people are working on the
same product as a team, all of them would
do the technical portions individually for
grading, but then, for the last three weeks
when it comes time to promote the project
in this portion of the class, you would switch
over and all three team members would work
together on promoting the product.
So that is the idea behind how teams would
work. For all non-final project individual
assignments, it goes without saying that you
should submit your answers as individuals.