So let's talk briefly about the syllabus and
the assignments for the course. You can take
the course for the technology or for the philosophy,
which is of a highly applied variety, or both.
Here is the Stanford Bulletin description
for the previous offering of the course. It
gives a good outline of many of the things
in it. We're structuring it somewhat differently,
but I present this for completeness. Here's
our schedule. So we start on June 17 and we
go until August 25, so exactly ten weeks or
seventy days. And homeworks go out on Wednesdays,
and they're due at 11:59PM on the following
Wednesday. After this point over here, the
final project starts, and the final project
winners (this is just bragging rights with
no money involved) are declared on August
25th at 11:59PM PST. We'll talk about the
final projects in a little bit.
In terms of the syllabus, this is a technical
component. We're going to start you off signing
up for web services, and progressively build
out your development environment, teach you
some CSS, some basic responsive design, front-end
javascript, back-end javascript, and build
up a fairly sophisticated application by the
end of this. Complementing this technical
portion, we also have a philosophical portion.
These weeks are meant to go together. The
philosophy that we introduce somewhat relates
to the technology. For example, here we talk
about design and PR and so on in the same
week we're learning about design and CSS and
those kinds of things. Here we talk about
sales, marketing, and funnel; and here you're
going through some degree of analytics and
cost-of-customer acquisition and whatnot.
These are meant to complement each other.
In terms of the assignments, there are graded
homeworks, which are the primary component
of your grade; they go out on Wednesdays;
standard multiple choice quizzes and programming
assignments in javascript. These are objective
answers that are autograded. As for the final
project, it is partially graded. You can see
the slides here for details. It is basically
a bitcoin powered self-starter, a crowd-funding
app that you will build up over the course
of the quarter and then fill it with your
own concept. What are graded are the technical
details of that application. What is not graded
is the qualitative content or the video, i.e.,
the product that you're building. That's not
graded. In typical what we're doing is we're
going to rank this on the base of the number
of bitcoins that you've raised and other kinds
of metrics that are hard to game, which we'll
talk about in a little bit.
As I've mentioned, the assignments are due
on Wednesdays. This is just a table that you
can consult to be totally definitive about
when things are going out and when they're
coming in. There are seven homeworks in total.
The first one is easy to allow a late start,
and the last one is short to allow project
focus. But the ones in the middle will be
reasonably challenging.