So let's talk about the final project for
a bit. We refer to it in the previous slides,
but let's go into it in detail. The idea is
that you're going to build your own simple
Bitcoin-powered, crowdfunding site, featuring
your own product. The idea here is that when
you've got 100,000 final projects, this presents
unique problems. You want to allow automatic
scoring and ranking, but also leave some room
for creativity. You want to enrich beginners,
but challenge advanced students. And you want
to complete it within a relatively short course
period, yet simulate as much of the founding
process as possible.
And after a lot of deliberation, what we're
doing is combining selfstarter and Bitcoin
(you can read about them over here). What
you're going to be doing is, over the course
of the quarter, programming your own node.js
version of selfstarter and adding in social
sharing, Bitcoin, and your product. Graphically,
you can think of it as this is the official
selfstarter open-source project, and you're
making a personal version of this to teach
yourself some web-programming, but also to
teach yourself many other aspects of building
a startup, customizing things, marketing things,
and whatnot. The social sharing aspects are
relatively straightforward; the Bitcoin aspect
is pretty interesting. The concept is that
we're going to grade the technical aspects
of that final project, but not the qualitative
aspects. For example, we will grade the fact
that you've got your "Hello World" site up
successfully at a URL and you've deployed
it, but not the name of your domain. Or we
will, for example, grade the fact that you
have your social and payment integrations
up, but not the look and feel of those integrations.
At the very end, the ungraded part is the
number of social shares and the number of
Bitcoin that you've raised, but this is really
for your bragging rights. All these things
are in terms of quality are for bragging rights
and for the quality of the product if you
want to take the class very seriously.
So, you choose the product, the text, the
video, design, and all the qualitative aspects
of the selfstarter. We can only autograde
the technical parts, but we allow your creativity
to shine through. The reason that we choose
Bitcoin in particular is that the class is
international and in that sense Bitcoin is
very good because you can do payments across
borders without transaction fees. Everyone
can get a merchant account setup within days;
they don't need to apply for banks. So for
a project that's teaching startups pedagogically,
that's extremely useful. But it's also very
good for this particular application because
Bitcoin transactions are world-readable. We
can see, for example, all the money that was
donated to this particular address by simply
going to a site like blockchain.info, and
see that this particular person at this address
received money at the following times and
in the following amounts, so we can see when
they started. So in this fashion, for example,
we can look at the Bitcoin address associated
with your project and see exactly how much
you've raised, and what time, and in what
quantities, and make sure that people are
not gaming the system. There will also be
a leaderboard. For example, example.com is
rated #1 in the genomics category. We're ranking
currently on the base of the number of Bitcoin
raised in their crowdfunder, but one could
also rank, for example, on the number of tweets
or Facebook shares involving example.com.
If we ranked by tweets, then example2.com
would actually rank #1, and it would also
be #1 in the law category. So let's talk by
categories for a second and prizes.
Oh, before we do that let's about some other
comments. We're going to review Bitcoin in
great detail later in the course, but you
can start by clicking these two links to go
and obtain some Bitcoin. But importantly,
buying Bitcoin is not needed to pass the course;
it's completely optional. The final project
is just meant to be hard to game. For those
who want to do something real, you can. Gaming
the process of getting a lot of money into
your Bitcoin account is a lot like running
a profitable company. For those who don't
want to do a real money crowdfunder, you can
maximize the number of Facebook or Twitter
shares instead.
Let's talk about prizes for a second. We're
going to have prizes in at least four categories.
After you fill out the survey, we'll likely
add more. You choose your category when you
enter the leaderboard, which will go live
later in class. As I've said, this is for
bragging rights only. What we'll do is rank
order and prizes in each category in each
class. To be counted as a winner, you would
have to be in one of the high positions on
the last day when the leaderboard is frozen
and the winners are announced. Remember again,
you don't need to participate in the public
leaderboard to get a 100% grade in the class,
and you don't need to use Bitcoin to compete
in the public competition. You can compete
solely on the number of social media shares.
But I like this as a concept because those
who want to take the class very seriously
can actually simulate a lot the process of
starting a company, raising money, and building
the tech for the product.