Welcome. This is the Startup Engineering course
on Coursera. My name is Balaji Srinivasan.
I'm going to be the primary instructor for
the course. We love to have you. This is the
first time that this course is being offered
as a MOOC. So, it's an experiment in many
ways. It's an ambitious course. Unlike a normal
course, I won't be able to speak to you in
real time after class, so I will look for
your comments on the forums, and will monitor
them closely. So, please do be active there.
So, OK, without further ado, let's get started.
So the title of the course is Startup Engineering.
This is just kind of the logistics slide.
I'm not going to read every little bit, but
this is the URL you signed up on, however
this is the primary class URL and this is
the forum URL, so make sure to bookmark this
one. In terms of you know kind of the motivation
behind the class, this is really the class
we wish we'd had before starting up our own
company, and in Vijay's case, his research
lab. It's a spiritual sequel to Peter Thiel's
CS 183, whereas that class was a hundred percent
philosophy, this class you can consider it
as fifty percent technology and fifty percent
philosophy. There's going to be multiple choice
and programming assignments like in the standard
class. There's also a final project. You're
going to be programming your own simple crowd
funding site and using it to market your own
startup idea. The final project will be partially
graded on the technical aspects of this crowd
funding site, but really you are going to
be doing for the public recognition, and for
the own satisfaction of building something.
You should go to forums, meetup and hackathons
over the course of the class, but it is an
individual class for the most part and you
should submit your own work. I'll have a comment
later in the slide on teams. Here are those
URLs again. This URL will be a convenience
URL. It will be updated later this week so
that you can kind of track the course materials
even when logged out. Importantly, with the
text book, all the notes are online. There's
nothing to buy. A task for help or report
bugs, please use the discussion forum rather
than email. There's a hundred thousand students,
so email will not scale.