Lets talk community and collaboration and
then summarize.
In terms of community and collaboration, we're
going to have many important guest lecturers
(which we are going to upload as the class
progresses) from many of the top startups
and big companies in Silicon Valley.
Forums, meet ups, and hackathons will be an
important part of the class. Please use the
discussion forums if you have questions, as
we will monitor them closely. As for meetups
and hackathons, read this forum thread, find
class meet ups in your city, create a thread
with your city if it doesn't exist (for example,
here's a New York forum thread meetup) and
if you live in a very remote area, use this
thread instead of Google hangouts with fellow
classmates.
Take pictures of meetups and link them from
the forum. The distinction here--and maybe
it's not that material--is you organize meetups
to go over the course material whereas hackathons
are really just about cranking on code. But
maybe those are the same thing, in your view.
In terms of the summary, then, the class basically
covers everything we wish we knew before starting
our companies or labs. There's going to be
a lot of Javascript and web programming. The
final project is building your own Bitcoin-powered
crowdfunder over the quarter and then using
it to market your own product.
Please go over these links to figure out what
to do next. Perhaps the most important bit
is to share the course signup link with any
friends that might be interested. After that,
you can continue here the next lecture in
Week 1. As for Homework 1, it will be out
Wednesday, and will be due on June 26th.
Welcome to the class. We're glad to have you!